SENIOR PRODUCT MANAGER

Summary

Accountable for researching and developing comprehensive solution services and marketing materials for vertical and horizontal markets. Devised comprehensive analysis reporting outlining consumer and industry-related IT trends that affected network and desktop outsourcing and for the retail industry. Served as key liaison between company and major external marketing firms in gathering information / statistics, brokering, and conducting calls. *Acted as lead project manager in executing various projects, developing bids / proposals, and creating marketing materials used in sales and marketing campaigns. INSIDE SALES REPRESENTATIVE Managed the entire lifecycle development process from initial prospecting, client identification, and needs assessment through negotiations, contracting, and service delivery. Conducted competitive market analysis and forecasting research to decipher consumer and industry trends resulting in the ability to devise high-impact sales strategies. *Played a key role in a new position pilot program for an inside service sales group; actively created sales training documentation for new position. *Met/exceeded new business lead generation 100%+ per month. ~ Prior Career History & Achievements Available Upon Request ~ Highlights

- Product Management
- Go-to-market strategy
- Business Development
- Strategic Business Planning
- Financial Analysis
- Process Improvements
- User Experience
- Usability Testing
- Agile Methodologies
- Waterfall Methodologies
- Process Improvements
- Competitive Analysis
- SharePoint
- Blueprint
- WebTrends
- Microsoft Office
- OneNote

Experience

01/2007 to Current

SENIOR PRODUCT MANAGER Alteryx i1/4 Portland, ME

- As product Subject Matter Expert (SME): lead product research and development based on Market and Competitive analysis, Sales
 initiatives, and current business needs of existing clients.
- Act as a consultant to Sales, Relationship Management, and other groups.
- Product lifecycle responsibilities for assigned product lines.
- Initiate and lead market research for product line working directly with clients, prospects, focus groups and other industry experts including internal groups to determine needs of the target marketplace.
- Develop product strategy roadmaps, project charters and market requirements based on research.
- Provide technical expertise in identifying, evaluating and developing systems and procedures that are operationally efficient, cost effective
 and meet user requirements.
- Ensure product readiness and operational delivery and support for new product launches.
- Deliver demos/presentations to prospects, clients, relationship managers and internal groups to capture accounts and guide sales.
- Key player in creating client adoption plans and leader in composing business requirements documents, Strength/Weakness/Opportunity/Threat (SWOT) analyses, and strategic business plans for individual products.
- Chase Champion recipient in Q1, Q3 and Q4 of 2016 for Exceeding Expectations and Doing the Right Thing.
- Collaborated with department leaders to orchestrate Webinar series for existing clients to support product enhancements, relationship development, and cross-selling opportunities.
- Over 1,000 merchant companies participated.
- Coordinate with Marketing to develop internal tool kits for new and existing products containing essential information / direction on
 presentations, business processes, online tutorials, product set-up, marketplace trends, target audience, cost analysis, case studies, pricing,
 and value propositions.
- Established quarterly product bulletin to educate staff on all product changes.
- Provide comprehensive product support to sales representatives, relationship managers and internal business teams.
- Research and resolve post-sales and post-installation issues.
- Defly balance multiple projects while concurrently supporting existing products to ensure top customer satisfaction.
- Work with outside consultants to gather competitive data for product enhancement or new product development.

01/2005 to 01/2007

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT REPRESENTATIVE Dispatchhealth i1/4 Nashville, TN

• Drove sales for an industry-leading provider of technology-based workforce solutions that reduce costs, increase productivity, improve employee satisfaction, and enhance service levels.

- Utilized outbound calling initiatives to cultivate and establish sales opportunities within targeted business accounts.
- Partnered with sales team to attain monthly quota via lead generation, extraction of sales intelligence from prospects, developing value, and establishing appointments with key decision-makers.
- Maintained comprehensive understanding of business issues and procurement process within technology-based environments.
- Play integral role in creating strategic sales campaigns by collaborating with corporate and field marketing.
- Met / exceeded lead generation goals 100%+ each quarter.
- Successfully completed an intensive sales training program.

01/2000 to 01/2005

Bickford Senior Living i1/4 Columbus, OH

 Advanced into positions of increased responsibility for a leading provider of international communication and technology solutions focusing on workspace management and application services.

Education

Master of Business Administration RIVIER COLLEGE i1/4 City, State

Bachelor of Science : Business Management MERRIMACK COLLEGE i1/4 City , State Business Management Skills

Agile, balance, Blueprint, Business Development, Strategic Business Planning, business plans, business processes, competitive, Competitive Analysis, consultant, cost analysis, client, clients, customer satisfaction, delivery, direction, Financial Analysis, focus, market research, market strategy, marketing, Market, Microsoft Office, SharePoint, new product development, presentations, pricing, procurement, Develop product, Product Management, product research, Relationship Management, Research, selling, Sales, sales training, strategy, strategic, Usability Testing, WebTrends